Guide to the Records of the New York Foundling Hospital 1869-2009 MS 347
New-York Historical Society
- Series XIV - Records of Children and Mothers (Restricted), 1869-1966
  - Subseries XIV.8 - St. Ann's Maternity Hospital (Restricted)
    - Registry of Births [RESTRICTED], 1905 January 1 - December 30 (Offsite-box 120, Volume 173)
    - Registry of Births [RESTRICTED], 1906 January 1 - December 31 (Offsite-box 120, Volume 174)
    - Registry of Births [RESTRICTED], 1907 January 1 - December 30 (Offsite-box 120, Volume 175)
    - Registry of Births [RESTRICTED], 1908 January 1 - December 30 (Offsite-box 120, Volume 176)
    - Registry of Births [RESTRICTED], 1909 January 1 - December 30 (Offsite-box 120, Volume 177)
    - Registry of Births [RESTRICTED], 1910 January 1 - December 30 (Offsite-box 120, Volume 178)
    - Registry of Births [RESTRICTED], 1911 January 4 - Deember 31 (Offsite-box 120, Volume 179)
    - Registry of Births [RESTRICTED], 1912 January 3 - December 26 (Offsite-box 120, Volume 180)
    - Registry of Births [RESTRICTED], 1913 January 1 - 1914 January 6 (Offsite-box 120, Volume 181)
    - Registry of Births [RESTRICTED], 1914 January 5 - 1915 January 6 (Offsite-box 120, Volume 182)
    - Registry of Births [RESTRICTED], 1915 January 1 - 1916 January 14 (Offsite-box 120, Volume 183)
    - Registry of Births [RESTRICTED], 1916 January 6 - December 21 (Offsite-box 120, Volume 184)
    - Registry of Births [RESTRICTED], 1916 December 22 - 1918 January 8 (Offsite-box 120, Volume 185)
    - Registry of Births [RESTRICTED], 1918 January 1 - December 25 (Offsite-box 120, Volume 186)
    - Registry of Births [RESTRICTED], 1918 December 30 - 1920 January 1 (Offsite-box 120, Volume 187)
    - Registry of Births [RESTRICTED], 1919 December 27 - 1920 December 30 (Offsite-box 120, Volume 188)
    - Registry of Births [RESTRICTED], 1920 December 27 - 1922 January 12 (Offsite-box 121, Volume 189)
    - Registry of Births [RESTRICTED], 1921 December 26 - 1923 January 14 (Offsite-box 121, Volume 190)
    - Registry of Births [RESTRICTED], 1923 January 2 - 1924 January 17 (Offsite-box 121, Volume 191)
    - Registry of Births [RESTRICTED], 1923 December 30 - 1924 July 4 (Offsite-box 121, Volume 192)
    - Registry of Births [RESTRICTED], 1924 June 21 - December 27 (Offsite-box 121, Volume 193)
    - Registry of Births [RESTRICTED], 1924 December 14 - 1925 July 2 (Offsite-box 121, Volume 194)
    - Registry of Births [RESTRICTED], 1925 June 27 - December 29 (Offsite-box 121, Volume 195)
    - Registry of Births [RESTRICTED], 1925 December 25 - 1926 July 2 (Offsite-box 121, Volume 196)
    - Registry of Births [RESTRICTED], 1926 June 22 - December 29 (Offsite-box 121, Volume 197)
    - Registry of Births [RESTRICTED], 1926 December 18 - 1927 June 27 (Offsite-box 121, Volume 198)
    - Registry of Births [RESTRICTED], 1927 June 24 - December 30 (Offsite-box 121, Volume 199)
    - Registry of Births [RESTRICTED], 1928 January 2 - June 30 (Offsite-box 121, Volume 200)
    - Registry of Births [RESTRICTED], 1928 June 27 - December 31 (Offsite-box 121, Volume 201)
    - Registry of Births [RESTRICTED], 1929 January 1 - July 19 (Offsite-box 121, Volume 202)
    - Registry of Births [RESTRICTED], 1929 July 7 - December 28 (Offsite-box 121, Volume 203)
    - Registry of Births [RESTRICTED], 1929 December 22 - 1930 June 30 (Offsite-box 121, Volume 204)
    - Registry of Births [RESTRICTED], 1930 July - December (Offsite-box 121, Volume 205)
    - Registry of Births [RESTRICTED], 1930 December - 1931 June (Offsite-box 121, Volume 206)
    - Registry of Births [RESTRICTED], 1931 July - December (Offsite-box 121, Volume 207)
    - Registry of Births [RESTRICTED], 1932 January - June (Offsite-box 121, Volume 208)
    - Registry of Births [RESTRICTED], 1932 July-December (Offsite-box 121, Volume 209)
    - Registry of Births [RESTRICTED], 1933 January-June (Offsite-box 121, Volume 210)
    - Registry of Births [RESTRICTED], 1933 July-December (Offsite-box 121, Volume 211)
    - Registry of Births [RESTRICTED], 1934 January-June (Offsite-box 122, Volume 212)
    - Registry of Births [RESTRICTED], 1934 July-December (Offsite-box 122, Volume 213)
    - Registry of Births [RESTRICTED], 1935 January-June (Offsite-box 122, Volume 214)
    - Registry of Births [RESTRICTED], 1935 July-December (Offsite-box 122, Volume 215)
    - Registry of Births [RESTRICTED], 1936 January-June (Offsite-box 122, Volume 216)
    - Registry of Births [RESTRICTED], 1936 July-December (Offsite-box 122, Volume 217)
    - Registry of Births [RESTRICTED], 1937 January-June (Offsite-box 122, Volume 218)
    - Registry of Births [RESTRICTED], 1937 July-December (Offsite-box 122, Volume 219)
    - Registry of Births [RESTRICTED], 1938 January-June (Offsite-box 122, Volume 220)
    - Registry of Births [RESTRICTED], 1938 July-December (Offsite-box 122, Volume 221)
    - Registry of Births [RESTRICTED], 1939 January-June (Offsite-box 122, Volume 222)
    - Registry of Births [RESTRICTED], 1939 July-December (Offsite-box 122, Volume 223)
    - Registry of Births [RESTRICTED], 1940 January-June (Offsite-box 122, Volume 224)
    - Registry of Births [RESTRICTED], 1940 July-December (Offsite-box 122, Volume 225)
    - Registry of Births [RESTRICTED], 1941 January-June (Offsite-box 122, Volume 226)
    - Registry of Births [RESTRICTED], 1941 July-December (Offsite-box 123, Volume 227)
    - Registry of Births [RESTRICTED], 1942 January-June (Offsite-box 123, Volume 228)
    - Registry of Births [RESTRICTED], 1942 July-December (Offsite-box 123, Volume 229)
    - Registry of Births [RESTRICTED], 1943 January-June (Offsite-box 123, Volume 230)
    - Registry of Births [RESTRICTED], 1943 July-December (Offsite-box 123, Volume 231)
    - Registry of Births [RESTRICTED], 1944 January-June (Offsite-box 123, Volume 232)
    - Registry of Births [RESTRICTED], 1944 July-December (Offsite-box 123, Volume 233)
    - Registry of Births [RESTRICTED], 1945 January-June (Offsite-box 123, Volume 234)
    - Registry of Births [RESTRICTED], 1945 July 1-September 29 (Offsite-box 123, Volume 235)
    - Registry of Births [RESTRICTED], 1945 September 30 - 1946 February 23 (Offsite-box 123, Volume 236)
    - St. Ann's Baptismal Records, 1910-1926 (Offsite-box 123, Volume 237)
    - St. Ann's Baptisms, 1926 March - 1934 May (Offsite-box 123, Volume 238)
  - Subseries XIV.9 - Autopsies (Restricted)
    - Record of Autopsies, 1931 October 8 - 1955 February 21 (Offsite-box 123, Volume 239)
- Series XV - Audiovisual Materials, 1958-2008 and undated
  The series consists of 12 boxes containing videotapes in various formats, DVDs, and 16mm film. Materials are arranged by format.
  The VHS tapes are arranged first, and are organized numerically using numbers originally assigned by Richard Reilly at the Foundling. Reilly further created a detailed guide to the content of each VHS cassette, which is available at the Manuscript Department of the New-York Historical Society. The VHS tapes most often contain segments of television news and talk shows. There are also some "home" videos of Foundling events and some promotional videos.
  Other formats were not catalogued by Reilly, or viewed by any archivist, and are described in this finding aid according to their labels.
  - VHS tapes numbered 1-15 (missing 7,9), 1992-1997 (Offsite-box 65)
  - VHS tapes numbered 16-28 (missing 25, 26; including 24A), 1958-2005 (Offsite-box 66)
  - VHS tapes numbered 29-45 (missing 33, 42, 43), 1986-1998 and undated (Offsite-box 67)
  - VHS tapes numbered 47-68 (missing 50, 55, 57-59, 61-63, 66), undated (pre-1958) - 2003 (Offsite-box 68)
  - VHS tapes numbered 69-88 (missing 70, 71, 74, 77, 85), 1989-2000 and undated (Offsite-box 69)
  - VHS tapes numbered 89-105 (missing 96, 100-102), circa 1983-2004 (Offsite-box 70)
  - Box of VHS and Beta: 1 VHS tape (transfer of 1950 Loretta Young promotional film); 11 Betacam SP tapes numbered 1-11 and labeled "NY Foundling Hospital Raw Footage"; 1 Sony Beta BCT-20K tape (numbered 1 of 11) dated 1987 April 27, 1987 and undated (Offsite-box 71)
  - Box of Beta and DVD: 10 Sony Beta BCT-20K videotapes (numbered 2-11; 1 in Box 71); 1 Fuji Betacam SP tape labeled "Sister Marilda Joseph" (1995) in a box labeled "Loretta Young Film"; 1 Sony Beta BCT-20K tape labeled "Eddie Albert Foundling Hospital, Roll #1, Master, 7 Aug. 1987", 4 DVDs: Promo Film 11/07; the Pajama Program 01/03/08; Orphan Train (undated); Loretta Young (undated transfer of 1950 promo film?); and "Abandon No One" (undated circa 2008), 1987, 1995, 2007, 2008 and undated (Offsite-box 72)
  - Box of 3/4" U-matic Video (twelve 4.75"x7.25" cassettes): 9 Sony KCS-20K tapes numbered 1-3 and 6-11, all labeled "Time Code Dub", dated 1987 May 26 and undated; 3 Sony KCS-20XBR tapes numbered 1-3 all labeled "Window Dub" and number 1 also labeled "St. Agatha's: Disabled Children and Bus Transportation" all undated (Offsite-box 73)
  - Box of 3/4" video (nine 5.5"x8.5" cassettes): 2 tapes labeled "CAS/Interpublic NY Foundling 'Short Version' 32:00 5/3/88"; 2 tapes labeled "CAS Interpublic NY Foundling 3/4 " Dub" - "Part I Approx 60 min. 9/25/92" and "Promotion Tape 20:40 11/11/92"; 1 undated tape labeled "Reaching Out: Child Care Programs of the Foundling Length 57:55; 2 undated tapes labeled "NY Foundling Window Dub" - 1 also labeled "CAS 462, 4-5" and 1 labeled "CAS 463, Roll 6"; 1 undated tape labeled "PB video project 3 teens/teenage girls by Abbie Fink"; 1 ABC video labeled "Program: People-Places-Things, Episode Title LC-13930, Super Family" dated 12/18/75, 1975-1992 and undated (Offsite-box 74)
  - Box of Betacam SP and 1" Video: 3 Sony Betacam SP tapes labeled Interpublic/CAS NYFH Video Project reels 1-5" dated 3/13/89; 1 Betacam SP tape labeled "Paramount Pictures and MTV Films the Fighting Temptations Electronic Press Kit" dated 9/4/03; 1 reel of 1" video labeled CAS/Interpublic NY Foundling "Crisis Nursery/Reaching Out" dated 5/3/88; 1 reel of 1" video labeled CAS/Interpublic Project Basement Hourglass" dated 4/11/89; 1 reel of 1" video labeled "CAS/Interpublic NY Foundling Promotion Tape" dated 11/11/92; 1 reel of 1" video labeled "CAS/Interpublic NY Foundling Home Part 2" dated 9/23/92, 1988-2003 (Offsite-box 75)
  - Box of three 16 mm films: "But What of the Child" English Version and Spanish version; and "WNBC TV Positively Black: New York Foundling (Foster Mothers)", undated (Offsite-box 76)
- Series XVI - Nurse's Capes, circa 1915-1965
  - 2 Nurse's Capes, circa 1915-1965 (Offsite-box OS 2)
- Series XVII - Published Books, 1951-2001
  The series consists of 14 books, kept by the Foundling for historical research. Twelve are published or self-published books, one is a photocopy of a published book, and one is a self-published manuscript.
  One book (Gottlieb/Yaffa) is about the New York Foundling Hospital as a whole. One book (by Cardinal Spellman) is a novel about a ward of the Foundling. Two books (Earley) are about the Sisters of Charity. One book (Walsh) is about St. Vincent's Hospital. Two books (Gordon and Brophy) are about the Foundling's "Arizona Incident" in 1904. Seven other books are about the orphan train, and most of these were published via the Orphan Train Heritage Society of America. There are duplicates of some of these orphan train books, as well as related books, in the Children's Aid Society Records, 1836-2006 (bulk 1853-1947) at the New-York Historical Society.
  The books are arranged alphabetically by title.
  - Dorothy Urch Charles Found at Last: A Story of the Orphan Trains (self-published manuscript), circa 2000 (Offsite-box 123, Volume 240)
  - Francis Cardinal Spellman The Foundling (New York: Charles Scribner's Sons, 1951) (Offsite-box 124, Volume 241)
  - Martin Gottlieb with contemporary photographs by Claire Yaffa The Foundling: The Story of the New York Foundling Hospital (New York: Norfleet Press, 2001) (Offsite-box 124, Volume 242)
  - A. Blake Brophy Foundlings on the Frontier: Racial and Religious Conflict in Arizona Territory, 1904-1905 (Tucson: University of Arizona Press, 1972) - photocopy only (Offsite-box 124, Volume 243)
  - Linda Gordon The Great Arizona Orphan Abduction (Cambridge and London: Harvard University Press, 1999) (Offsite-box 124, Volume 244)
  - Mary Ellen Johnson, editor Journeys of Hope: Orphan Train Riders Their Own Stories (Orphan Train Heritage Society of America, 1999) (Offsite-box 124, Volume 245)
  - Mary Ellen Johnson and Kay B. Hall, editors Orphan Train Riders: Their Own Stories Volume 1 (Baltimore: Gateway Press, 1992) (Offsite-box 124, Volume 246)
  - Mary Ellen Johnson and Kay B. Hall, editors Orphan Train Riders: Their Own Stories Vol. 2 (Baltimore: Gateway Press, 1993) (Offsite-box 124, Volume 247)
  - Mary Ellen Johnson et. al., editors Orphan Train Riders: Their Own Stories Volume 4 (Baltimore: Gateway Press, 1997) (Offsite-box 124, Volume 248)
  - Michael D. Patrick and Evelyn Goodrich Trickel Orphan Trains to Missouri (Columbia: University of Missouri Press, 1997) (Offsite-box 125, Volume 249)
  - Mary Elizabeth Earley, S.C. The Sisters of Charity of New York 1960-1996 Volume IV (New York: Sisters of Charity of New York Press, 1997) (Offsite-box 125, Volume 250)
  - Mary Elizabeth Earley, S.C. The Sisters of Charity of New York 1960-1996 Volume V (New York: Sisters of Charity of New York Press, 1997) (Offsite-box 125, Volume 251)
  - Patricia J. Young and Frances E. Marks Tears on Paper: Orphan Train History including Stories as Told by Nebraska Orphan Train Riders (self published, 1990) (Offsite-box 125, Volume 252)
  - Sister Marie De Lourdes Walsh With a Great Heart: The Story of St. Vincent's Hospital and Medical Center of New York 1849-1964 (New York: St. Vincent's Hospital, 1965) (Offsite-box 125, Volume 253)